Hello everyone. So today we are going to continue the discussion about the storage devices.
大家好。所以今天我们将继续讨论存储设备。
In particular, we are going to talk about SSDs or solid state devices, and we are going
特别是，我们将要谈论SSD或固态设备，并且我们将要
to start the discussion on queuing theory. So last time we talked about disk drives or
开始讨论排队理论。上次我们谈到了磁盘驱动器或者
the spinning disks, and these are the main technologies used to store data for the first
旋转盘片，这些是用于首次存储数据的主要技术。
few decades of personal computers and computers in general. And we are starting with kind
几十年来的个人电脑和计算机的发展。我们从种类开始。
of two decades ago, a little bit more than that. We started to see the emergence of another
二十多年前，稍微多一点。我们开始看到另一个的出现。
technology to store data persistently, and that was memory-based. And the first efforts
技术用于持久存储数据，而且是基于内存的。而且最初的努力是
was in 1995, the emergencies of you have DRAM, but how you make it persistent? Well, you
在1995年，你们有DRAM的紧急情况，但是你们如何使其持久化？好的，你们可以通过以下方式实现：
have a battery, you have DRAM powered by a battery. And then as long as the battery lasts,
你有一个电池，你有由电池供电的DRAM。只要电池还有电，
you are going to store the data persistently in that memory, even when the computer is
你将会将数据持久地存储在那个内存中，即使电脑关闭。
unplugged. But after that, things change with this new technology, NAND, multi-level cell.
拔掉插头。但是在那之后，随着这种新技术的出现，事情发生了变化，那就是NAND多级单元。
So basically this allows you to store, it's like a memory, but it allows you to store
所以基本上这个可以让你存储，就像一个记忆，但它可以让你存储什么？
data, to store information, even when it's not powered. So that was kind of the key technology
数据，用于存储信息，即使在没有电源的情况下也能保持。所以这就是关键技术。
innovation at a high level. Of course, there are many details, we don't have a lot of time
创新水平很高。当然，还有很多细节，我们没有太多时间。
to go into details, but the big thing was about having this commercially available technology
不详细说明，但重要的是拥有这种商业化技术。
to store data in this new kind of memories without needing to power them on.
将数据存储在这种新型的存储器中，无需将其通电。
And these SSDs, they store information, granularity of a memory block, and the memory block consists
这些SSD存储设备，它们存储信息，以内存块的粒度为单位，而内存块则由...
of four kilobytes, between four and 64 kilobytes pages. And remember that 40 kilobytes pages
每个页面的大小为4千字节，介于4千字节至64千字节之间。请记住，页面大小为40千字节。
is basically more or less like a sector on a disk, disk drive. And it's also making the
是基本上类似于磁盘驱动器上的一个扇区。它也在制造
size of the page for a virtual memory implementation. So you have virtual memory, the pages in the
虚拟内存实现中的页面大小。所以你有虚拟内存，页面的大小是多少？
virtual memory are typically four kilobytes, the same, the size is a sector size. And then
虚拟内存通常为四千字节，与扇区大小相同。然后
when you translate those to the SSDs, you are going for this four kilobytes page are
当你将这些内容翻译成SSDs时，你要选择这个四千字节的页面。
part of a memory block and the memory block consists of four between four and 64 pages.
一部分是内存块，而内存块由4到64个页面组成。
This is an important detail. There are no moving parts, just like memory. So this has
这是一个重要的细节。没有任何可动部件，就像内存一样。所以这个有
a certain advantages, big advantages. First of all, eliminate the seek and the rotation
某些优势，非常大的优势。首先，消除寻道和旋转。
latency. Remember from last time, there's a seek and rotation latency, where is the
寻道延迟和旋转延迟。记得上次说过，有寻道延迟和旋转延迟，它们在哪里呢？
biggest culprits of a long latency to access data on the disk, at least randomly. That's
磁盘访问数据延迟最长的罪魁祸首，至少在随机访问时。
why we have a huge difference between the throughput of a disk when you access the data
为什么在访问数据时，磁盘的吞吐量会有很大差异？
sequentially, because in that particular case, you do not need to pay for the seek and rotation
按顺序，因为在这种特殊情况下，您不需要支付寻道和旋转的费用。
delays, versus when you access the data randomly, when you need to pay for both of these delays,
延迟，相对于当你随机访问数据时，当你需要为这两种延迟付费时，
seeks and rotation. They also have requires even very low power and anything, and they
寻求和旋转。它们还需要非常低的功耗和任何东西，以及它们
are lightweight. It's not just memory. It's not like a disk metal with platters spinning
是轻巧的。不仅仅是内存。它不像一个有盘片旋转的金属磁盘。
and heads and things like that. On the downside, it does have limited write cycles. So this
而且还有头部和类似的东西。不过，它的写入次数有限，这是一个缺点。所以这个
means that limited write cycle, it's when you modify a cell, when you modify a bit,
这意味着有限的写入周期，即当您修改一个单元格时，修改一个位时，
if you modify it too many times, if you write the same bit too many times, then it works
如果你修改它太多次，如果你写同样的部分太多次，那么它就会起作用。
out. You can no longer write that bit reliably. So that's one of the challenges you need to
面对的挑战之一是，你无法再可靠地写下那一部分。
deal with. And obviously, since you already introduced, there are rapid advantage and
处理。显然，既然你已经介绍了，那就有快速的优势和
the capacity have increased. And today, to give you a sense, obviously today is that
容量已经增加。今天，为了让你有个概念，显然今天是这样的。
I'm not sure any of your devices you are working with still has a disk, unless you are working,
我不确定你正在使用的任何设备上是否还有磁盘，除非你正在工作。
you have a big workstation home or you are using. But certainly your laptops, obviously
你有一个大的工作站在家里或者你正在使用。但是肯定你也有笔记本电脑，显然的。
the phones, the IP or iPad, they no longer have disk drives to store data persistently.
手机、IP或iPad，它们不再具备磁盘驱动器来持久存储数据。
They only have SSDs. So here it's again how SSD architecture look like. This NAND is where
它们只有固态硬盘（SSD）。所以这里再次介绍一下SSD的架构是什么样的。这个NAND是其中的一部分。
on the right hand side is the memory, the banks of memory, and each of these could present
在右手边是内存，内存的银行，每个银行都可以呈现。
a block. And then you have a flash memory controller, which basically decides where
一个块。然后你有一个闪存控制器，它基本上决定了在哪里。
to write and what to read the data from. And you have a buffer manager and the software
来写入和读取数据的位置。而且你还有一个缓冲区管理器和软件。
queue. And this is about when this is where you buffer the reads and writes requests.
排队。这是关于在这里缓冲读写请求的地方。
So if you have many reads or writes requests at the same time, and you cannot serve at
同时有很多读取或写入请求，而且无法同时处理的话，
the same time, you have to buffer them and serve them one by one. It's also a DRAM here.
同时，你需要将它们缓冲并逐个提供。这里也有一个DRAM。
So when you cache some of the information, right, when you read, if I read only a few
所以当你缓存一些信息时，对吗？当你阅读时，如果我只读了一小部分
bytes, the granularity, if you remember to read and write from this SSD, it's one of
字节，粒度，如果你记得从这个固态硬盘读写，它是其中之一。
these memory blocks, which can be between 16 and 256 kilobytes. So you have to read
这些内存块的大小可以在16到256千字节之间。所以你需要读取。
that granularity. And once you are reading it, you are going to cache it, because if
那种细粒度。而且一旦你读取它，你就会将其缓存，因为如果
you are going to read again the next few bytes, then it's already in DRAM. You don't need
你将再次读取接下来的几个字节，然后它们已经在DRAM中了。你不需要
to go and fetch it again. And now, this is the SATA, it's bus technology,
去重新取回它。现在，这是SATA，它是一种总线技术，
and or can be PS, which is connected through a bridge to the PCI bus, like we discussed
and 或者可以是 PS，它通过桥接器连接到 PCI 总线，就像我们讨论过的那样。
last time, and then it's connected to the processor and to the memory.
上次，然后它连接到处理器和内存。
So here are some numbers for you. To read a 4 kilobyte page, it takes around, say, between
这里有一些数字给你。读取一个4千字节的页面大约需要，比如说，大约需要多少时间？
10 and 25 microseconds. Again, there is no SQL rotation latency. So now the transfer
10和25微秒。再次强调，没有SQL旋转延迟。所以现在进行传输。
time for a 4 kilobyte page for the SATA interface, you have between 300 and 600 megabytes per
时间为SATA接口的4千字节页面，你有300到600兆字节的空间。
second. Actually, the best interface is today you have 2 gigabytes per second, so a few
秒。实际上，最好的接口是今天你有每秒2千兆字节，所以只需要几个
times larger than this. But even for, say, 400 megabytes per second to take a number,
比这个大400兆字节每秒，但即使是以每秒400兆字节的速度来说，
then the transfer time, so the time to read 4 kilobyte pages is 10 microseconds. And the
然后是传输时间，所以读取4千字节页面的时间是10微秒。而且
latency, if you remember, what is the latency? The queuing time, so the time the request
延迟，如果你还记得的话，延迟是什么？排队时间，也就是请求的时间。
has to wait in the queue for the request to be satisfied, and plus the controller time,
必须在队列中等待请求被满足，并加上控制器的时间，
whatever the controller needs to do and to make the decision, it's a fixed time, and
无论控制器需要做什么和做出什么决策，都是在固定的时间内完成的。
the transfer time. And because this is a memory, basically you can randomly address, there
传输时间。由于这是一种存储器，基本上可以随机寻址，因此您可以随意访问。
is not such a big difference between sequential and random reads.
顺序读和随机读之间的差异并不是很大。
Now this was about the read. Now the writing is much more complex. And you can only write
现在这是关于阅读的。现在写作要复杂得多。而且你只能写。
empty pages in a block. So there are three states of these pages. It's written, no, two
块中的空白页。所以这些页有三种状态。有写入的，没有，还有两个。
stages, whether it's written or whether it's erased or empty. And you can only write empty
阶段，无论是书写的还是擦除的或者是空白的。而且你只能书写空白的。
pages. So if you want to overwrite a page, then before doing that, you need to erase
页面。所以如果你想覆盖一个页面，在这之前，你需要先擦除。
a page. And now the page becomes empty and then you overwrite it. Now, the problem with
一个页面。现在这个页面变成了空白，然后你覆盖了它。现在，问题出在
that is that this operation is far more expensive. Remember, it's like the read was say 25 microseconds.
这就是说这个操作要贵得多。记住，就像读取需要25微秒一样。
The writing data on an empty page is 200 microseconds. And now if you want to erase a page, if you
想要擦除一页的话，现在的擦除时间是多少？
need to erase a page, if you don't have an empty page, erasing the page takes 1.5 milliseconds.
需要擦除一页，如果没有空白页，擦除一页需要1.5毫秒。
So the rule of thumb you can think about, the write is 10 times more expensive than
所以你可以考虑的经验法则是，写作比阅读贵十倍。
the reads and the erasers are 10 times more expensive than the writes. So 200 microseconds,
读取和擦除的价格是写入的10倍。所以200微秒，
it's around eight times larger than 25 microseconds, which is a time to read a page. And then 1.5
它大约是25微秒的八倍大，这是读一页的时间。然后是1.5。
milliseconds is what? 7.5 times larger than 200 microseconds is the time to write an empty
毫秒是什么？7.5倍于200微秒的时间是写入一个空的时间。
page. So therefore you need to be very careful about that. So this is the thing, the two
页。因此，你需要非常小心。所以这就是问题，这两个
constraints you have to operate with. And the two constraints which are different make
你必须遵守的限制条件。而这两个不同的限制条件产生了不同的影响。
this SSD different than the DRAMs, the traditional memory. It's one, it's about you can only
这个SSD与DRAM和传统内存不同。它是一种，它是关于你只能
write empty pages and read and writes are asymmetric, are not taking the same amount
写空白页和读写操作是不对称的，它们所需的时间不相等。
of time, eraser take even longer. So this is one. And the other one is that you can
在时间方面，橡皮擦需要更长的时间。所以这是一个。另一个是你可以
only do a limited amount, a number of writes. Typically it's like 10,000 writes or something
只能进行有限次数的写入操作。通常是10,000次写入或者类似的数量。
like that. Okay. So you need to be careful. So now in order to avoid the cost of erasure,
那样。好的。所以你需要小心。为了避免擦除的费用，现在
when you need to write, so to erase first before writing, what the controller is doing,
当你需要写东西时，所以在写之前先擦除，控制器在做什么？
it maintains a pool of empty blocks. So you bring the use pages, put them in a, you know,
它维护了一个空块的池子。所以你把使用过的页面放进去，放在一个，你知道的，
put together in a block and then it pulls, you have these pools of empty blocks and then
将它们组合成一个块，然后它会被拉动，你会得到一些空块的池子，然后...
you can write them and then you can pay only 200 microseconds per page instead of 1.7 milliseconds.
您可以将它们写下来，然后每页只需支付200微秒，而不是1.7毫秒。
SSDs provide the same interface as hard disk drives to the OS, the same API, which is great
SSDs提供与操作系统相同的接口，与硬盘驱动器相同的应用程序接口（API），这非常好。
because you can just swap a disk drive with an SSD and the computer will work, but it
因为你只需要将硬盘驱动器换成固态硬盘(SSD)，电脑就能正常工作，但是
will be much faster. Right? Like I said, when you override the data, when you, the chronology
将会快得多。对吗？就像我说的，当你覆盖数据时，当你，时间顺序
of writing, it's a, it's a block and the block can be 16 times larger than a page, sorry,
写作的话，它是一个，它是一个块，这个块可以比一页大16倍，抱歉，
64 times larger than a page. So you have a page is four kilobytes and you have 64 pages
一个页面比一个页面大64倍。所以你有一个页面是四千字节，你有64个页面。
in a block. Then 64 by time of times four is 256 kilobytes. So this is what the 256
在一个块中。然后64乘以四次是256千字节。所以这就是256。
kilobytes is coming from. Okay. So I, we already discussed about it. Why not erase and rewrite
千字节是从哪里来的。好的。所以，我们已经讨论过了。为什么不删除并重写呢？
new version of the entire 256 blocks? Because erasure is extremely slow. And then each block
整个256个区块的新版本？因为擦除非常慢。然后每个区块
has a finite lifetime. Like I mentioned to you, you cannot erase and rewrite all the
有一个有限的寿命。就像我之前跟你提到的，你不能擦除和重写所有的
time. You can only do that for say 10, a few tens of that 10 thousands of times. Okay.
时间。你只能这样做十次，大约十万次的几十倍。好的。
So therefore if you have heavily used blocks, you do a lot of writes, they are going to
所以，如果你使用的块很多，写入操作也很频繁，那么它们会
wear out quickly. Okay. So now you have this problem, right? It's like, you know, you,
穿得很快就破了。好的。所以现在你有这个问题，对吧？就像，你知道的，你，
you have if you have, how, how do you are going to solve it? Right. And again, the problem
你有的话，你会怎么解决呢？对的。再次，问题是什么？
is that, you know, I cannot, I can do, I am allowed to do only a limited number of writes
这意味着，你知道的，我不能，我只能做，我只被允许做有限数量的写入操作。
and now I have some heavy blocks. So what I'm going to do about it, do you have any
现在我有一些沉重的障碍。那么我该怎么办呢，你有什么建议吗？
suggestions here?
这里有什么建议吗？
Remap. That's exactly, that's very good. So basically when you are going to rewrite, you
重新映射。没错，非常好。所以基本上当你要重写时，你需要重新映射。
are not going to rewrite in the same place. You are going to write to another page, which
不会在同一个地方重写。你将要写到另一页，这一页是...
is not, was not so used in the past. And then you are going to remap the, the page to the
过去并没有这样使用。然后你打算重新映射页面，将其重新定位到
new block. You're you're you're used to write the new information. And this is a layer of
新的区块。你可以用它来写入新的信息。这是一个层级。
indirection. It is called flash translation layer or FTL in SSD. I assume maps, the virtual
间接寻址。在固态硬盘中，它被称为闪存转换层或FTL。我假设地图，虚拟的
block numbers, which is uses these are the blocks actually says a page numbers, the physical
阻止数字，这些数字是指页面上实际显示的页码，即物理页码。
page numbers, which flash memory control uses. Okay. So that's the way it's it's working.
页码，闪存控制器使用的。好的。所以这就是它的工作方式。
Right. So from the OS perspective, you still have the same page as the same page numbers
对的。所以从操作系统的角度来看，你仍然将同一页面视为相同的页面编号。
and everything, but now on the physical pages, you have a map and the page number as seen
和其他所有东西一样，但现在在实体页面上，你会看到一张地图和页码。
by the CPU is going to map to a physical page number. And the mapping is, it's, it's, it's,
由CPU将映射到一个物理页码。而这个映射是，它是，它是，它是，
it's managed by the controller. So the controller can remap and basically say page number one
它由控制器管理。因此，控制器可以重新映射并基本上指定为第一页。
is go to physical page number 10 and next is going to go to physical page number 15.
去物理页码10，然后再去物理页码15。
Right. So that's why, how I'm going to load balance the writes for the same page as seen
正确。所以这就是为什么，我要如何对同一页的写入进行负载均衡。
by the CPU. Okay. So this is pretty much it. It's again, copy on write. This is, or should
由CPU执行。好的。所以基本上就是这样。再次强调，这是写时复制。这是，或者应该是。
be obvious, right? Again, I do not want to copy to rewrite the same page. You know, even
显而易见，对吧？再说一遍，我不想复制重写同样的页面。你知道，即使
if I want to modify a page, I don't rewrite it because I need to erase it first. And if
如果我想修改一个页面，我不会重写它，因为我需要先将其删除。而且如果
I need to erase it first is expensive. So what I'm doing, I'm going to just create a
我需要先擦除它是很贵的。所以我现在要做的是，我只是要创建一个
new version of the page and I'm, then I'm going to remap it. Isn't the lifetime of 10k
页面的新版本，然后我打算重新映射它。寿命不是10k吗？
eraser writes quite small, consider that we can use a laptop for multiple years. It's
橡皮擦写得很小，考虑到我们可以使用笔记本电脑多年。
not really, I mean, because if you really do load balancing, really load balancing,
不是真的，我的意思是，如果你真的做负载均衡，真正的负载均衡，
this means that you need to write or update, you can read and draft and update. Like say
这意味着你需要写作或更新，你可以阅读、起草和更新。就像说的那样。
you have one terabyte of disk, right? So one terabyte of disk, then you can write the equivalent
你有一块1TB的硬盘，对吗？那么一块1TB的硬盘，你可以写入相当于多少的内容呢？
of 10,000 multiply with one terabyte. So 10 petabytes, right? I think this is right. You
一万乘以一太字节。所以是10拍字节，对吗？我认为是这样的。
can write 10 petabytes and you don't, you know, it's hard to write 10 petabytes. Yeah.
你可以写10个拍字节，而你不会，你知道的，写10个拍字节很难。是的。
So yeah. But it's again, this works if you are going to be able to load balance, right?
是的。但是这只适用于你能够进行负载均衡的情况下，对吗？
And this writes, right? And this is what the controller is doing.
是的，这是正确的。这是控制器正在做的事情。
Okay. The flash translation layer also ensures that there is no need to erase and rewrite
好的。闪存翻译层还确保不需要擦除和重写。
the entire 256 blocks when making small modification or changes. SSD controller can assign mapping
在进行小的修改或更改时，需要整个256个块。SSD控制器可以分配映射。
to spread or load, it's what we talk about. So you want basically to load balance the
分发或加载，这是我们讨论的内容。所以你基本上想要进行负载均衡。
writes. This is called where labeling, and you are doing that by remapping and doing
这被称为标注，你通过重新映射和执行来完成。
copy on write, creating new versions of the page or hopefully using a page, a physical
复制写入，创建页面的新版本，或者希望使用一个页面，一个物理的。
page which was not written many times. If you old version of the pages, which are, you
页面没有被多次编辑过。如果你需要旧版本的页面，它们是存在的。
know, you delete a file, what happened? Then they are very garbage collected in the background
了解，当你删除一个文件时，会发生什么？然后它们会在后台被很好地垃圾回收。
and in the background you are going to erase them. So to maybe to prepare them to be written
并且在背景中你将要抹去它们。所以也许是为了准备它们被书写。
again. So you, they are ready to be written again. Any questions?
再次。所以你们，他们准备好重新写了。有任何问题吗？
This again was something, some of the most, you know, now how they compare like hard disk
这又是一些东西，一些最，你知道的，现在他们如何比较，就像硬盘一样。
drives with SSDs. We'll have that in the next slide. But about SSDs themselves, you know,
使用固态硬盘（SSD）进行驱动。我们将在下一张幻灯片中介绍这个。但是关于SSD本身，你知道，
you can buy, and these are two years old, some of the data, but you can buy 16 terabytes.
你可以购买这些数据，它们已经有两年的历史了，但你可以购买16TB的容量。
You remember that we have 16 terabytes, the disk we considered last time, was this kind
你记得我们有16TB的硬盘，上次考虑的那个硬盘就是这个吗？
of the hard disk drive was having the same size, 16 terabytes, the same capacity. But
硬盘驱动器的大小都是相同的，16TB，容量也相同。但是
that was, if I remember correctly, and you can check, that was around $500, $550 or something
那是，如果我没记错的话，你可以查证一下，大约是500美元，550美元左右。
like that. This is $5,000. Okay. So it's 10 times more expensive. Okay. For the same capacity.
就是这样。这是5000美元。好的。所以它贵了10倍。好的。容量相同。
However, if you look at reads and writes, the number of sequential reads and writes,
然而，如果你看一下读取和写入的数量，顺序读取和写入的数量，
it's 800 or 900. In that case was, if I remember correctly, it's 800 or 900.
是800或900。如果我没记错的话，那个情况下是800或900。
sequential writes it was 260 megabytes per second. So this is up to four, almost four times faster.
顺序写入速度为每秒260兆字节。所以这个速度提高了将近四倍，达到了四倍快。
And random reads and writes, there is no comparison. Okay. You can have 100,000
和随机读写相比，没有可比性。好的。你可以拥有100,000。
reads per second. While a read in the case of a disk, if you remember, can take a few milliseconds.
每秒读取次数。如果你还记得，磁盘的读取操作可能需要几毫秒的时间。
So if you if you take even a few milliseconds and in a second, you can read a few hundreds
所以，如果你只需要几毫秒，一秒钟内你就可以读几百个。
or a few hundreds reads and writes. So in order to write it better. Okay. And if you go and if
或者几百次读写。所以为了更好地写它。好的。如果你去，如果
you really want to go to the top ones, you have 100 terabytes. So SSD 100 terabytes, and you have
你真的想要去买最高配置的，你有100TB的存储空间。所以你需要购买100TB的固态硬盘。
500 megabytes sequential read and writes, the same kind of IOPS 100 kilobytes. IOPS means
500兆字节的顺序读写，相同类型的IOPS为100千字节。IOPS是指每秒输入/输出操作数。
or input operation per second. Unlimited writes for five years, so you get these guarantees.
或者每秒输入操作。五年内无限写入，所以您可以获得这些保证。
But it costs 4000, $40,000. But more, far more expensive, right? It's like a quarter of dollar
但它要价4000美元，也就是40,000美元。但是更贵，远远更贵，对吧？就像是四分之一美元那么多。
per gigabyte. Why would random versus sequential have different performance? This is this.
每千兆字节。为什么随机读取和顺序读取会有不同的性能？这是这样的。
If you read at the level of pages, there is no difference. And you can do probably you can do
如果你按页数阅读，没有什么区别。而且你可能可以做到。
the math here. Or it's very little difference. But still, if you read at the level of page,
这里的数学。或者差别很小。但是，如果你以每页的水平阅读，
you know, because you transfer from the SSDs as a level of page or block, right,
你知道，因为你是以页面或块的级别从SSD传输的，对吧？
block granularity, if you read only one byte, or from that page, you are still going to lose
块粒度，如果你只读取一个字节，或者从那一页读取，你仍然会丢失数据。
in terms of performance or throughput. And the difference between random, the different reads
在性能或吞吐量方面。以及随机读取和不同读取之间的差异。
and writes, the reason is different here is because remember that the writes are slower,
并且写的原因不同是因为记住写作速度较慢，
10 times slower almost.
几乎慢了10倍。
Okay, so here is a comparison between hard disk drives and SSDs. And this is a nice,
好的，这里是硬盘驱动器和固态硬盘之间的比较。而且这是一个很好的，
interesting plot. Because, you know, why wouldn't use SSDs? They have all they are faster,
有趣的情节。因为，你知道，为什么不使用固态硬盘呢？它们都更快，
they can have bigger capacity, they consume less power. So they are probably, you know,
它们可以拥有更大的容量，消耗更少的电力。所以它们很可能，你知道的，
they are more reliable. So why in the world you wouldn't use them? Well, the answer is simply
它们更可靠。那么为什么你不使用它们呢？嗯，答案很简单。
it's cost, right? And however, and here what you see is a blue line is a flash cost. It is for
是费用，对吗？然而，这里你看到的是一个蓝线，是一个闪光费用。它是用于...
and for the same capacity for the terabyte is a flash cost or a terabyte. And here is
对于相同容量的存储设备，一兆字节的闪存成本或一兆字节的硬盘成本是相同的。这里是...
orange is hard disk drive cost. So the hard disk drives cost much cheaper than SSDs. And with green,
橙色是指硬盘驱动器的成本。因此，硬盘驱动器的成本比固态硬盘便宜得多。而且，使用绿色的话，
and the green is the most important curve, is basically what is the ratio between the cost to
绿色曲线是最重要的曲线，基本上是成本与
store one terabyte on an SSD versus the cost to store a terabyte on a hard disk drive.
将一TB存储在固态硬盘(SSD)上的成本与将一TB存储在机械硬盘(HDD)上的成本进行比较。
So it was 37 times in 2013. Today it's around five, six times. So it's much smaller. And many
所以在2013年是37倍。今天大约是五六倍。所以它小得多。而且很多
people predict that sometime in the future, these predictions are almost always wrong. But some in
人们预测在未来的某个时候，这些预测几乎总是错误的。但是有些人则持不同观点。
the near future, the SSD will match the cost of hard disk drives. And at that point, there is very
近期内，固态硬盘（SSD）的价格将与传统硬盘驱动器相匹配。到那时，将会有非常大的
little reasons to use hard disk drives at all. Okay. So in summary, SSDs, they have low latency,
快速响应时间，高速读写速度，耐用性强，体积小巧，无噪音，低功耗，易于携带，适用于各种设备和应用。
high throughput, no moving parts, more reliables, lower power consumptions, and read much faster,
高吞吐量，无动件，更可靠，功耗更低，读取速度更快。
read, you know, read at memory speeds. You can read even faster if you have a wider
阅读，你知道的，以内存速度阅读。如果你有更宽的阅读范围，你甚至可以阅读得更快。
bus by the way. That was one of the main limitations of how fast you can read and write.
顺便说一下，公交车。那是阅读和写作速度的主要限制之一。
The cons before the R2 is expensive, between 3 and 20x more expensive, but in a few years back,
R2之前的缺点是昂贵，价格在3到20倍之间，但在几年前的情况下，
like certainly 10 years back, the SSDs are much smaller than hard disk drives. So that's why
就像10年前一样，固态硬盘(SSD)比传统硬盘驱动器要小得多。这就是为什么。
here it's smaller storage. And the people back then, they are combining the hard disk drive
这里的存储空间较小。而且那时候的人们，他们正在结合硬盘驱动器。
with SSDs, using SSDs as a cache to get the performance of SSDs and to get the capacity
使用SSD作为缓存，以获得SSD的性能和容量。
of hard disk drives. But now it's no longer needed. Because as you've seen from the data,
硬盘驱动器的需求已经不再存在了。因为从数据上可以看出，
now the SSDs can have higher capacities than hard disk drives. Quite amazing.
现在固态硬盘（SSD）的容量可以比传统硬盘驱动器（HDD）更大。相当令人惊讶。
So this says, tells you, this technology, if you are to build a company based on that,
这段话的意思是，如果你打算基于这项技术创办一家公司，
it wouldn't have been a great idea because the trends are not in your favor.
这不是一个好主意，因为趋势不利于你。
Because your product to use SSDs to speed up the hard disk drives would have become obsolete.
因为您的产品使用SSD来加速硬盘驱动器，所以已经过时了。
There's still a reason to do that, because if you want to get the cost of the hard disk drives
还有一个原因要这样做，因为如果你想要得到硬盘驱动器的成本。
to do cheaper, right, to be cheaper and still have almost performance comparable to SSDs.
降低成本，对吧，要更便宜，但仍然具有与固态硬盘几乎相当的性能。
But that's probably true today. But in a few years, again, if SSDs are going to drop at the
但这可能是今天的事实。但是再过几年，如果固态硬盘的价格会下降的话，
cost of hard disk drives, this is really there is no reason for these optimizations.
硬盘驱动器的成本，这真的没有理由进行这些优化。
You have asymmetric block rights performance. We know that. And we learn about that. And you have
不对称的区块权益表现。我们知道这一点。我们也了解到了。而且你有...
the where, the limited lifetime in terms of writing rights. So you need to be careful.
在写作权方面，有一个有限的使用期限。所以你需要小心。
And average failure rate is six years. Life expenditures between nine and 10,
平均故障率为六年。寿命支出在九到十之间。
11 years, are actually better than hard disk drives. So it's again, the TLDR here,
11年，实际上比硬盘驱动器更好。所以，总结一下，
SSDs are better in almost every respect. You need to be more careful. It's more complex.
SSD在几乎所有方面都更好。你需要更加小心。这更加复杂。
The algorithms are more complex to go around these limitations. The erasures are very expensive and
算法更复杂以应对这些限制。擦除操作非常昂贵，而且
you need to erase a page before writing it. And the where, you need to take into account the
你需要在写之前擦掉一页。而在哪里，你需要考虑到
wearing of pages. And it's more expensive, but the costs are dropping. So the prices are dropping.
穿着页面。而且它更贵，但成本正在下降。所以价格也在下降。
Okay. So there's a question here. Just wondering how much overhead generally is there for the
Okay. 这里有一个问题。只是想知道一般来说有多少额外开销。
hybrid alternative system involving both SSD and hard disk drives? It seems like it would be a lot
混合替代系统，同时使用固态硬盘和机械硬盘？这似乎会更加复杂。
more complex keeping track going between both in the same computer. It's more complex, but the way
更复杂的是在同一台计算机上同时跟踪两者之间的转换。这样做更复杂，但方法是
you buy that, you buy this like, you buy that like, it's like, it's the same enclosure. The
你买那个，你买这个，就像你买那个一样，就像，它们是同样的包装。
hard disk drive, they are not two different devices. You buy like, it's like a device which
硬盘驱动器，它们不是两个不同的设备。你购买的就像是一个设备，它包含了一个硬盘和一个驱动器。
you plug into your SATA bus. Right. And like, you'll buy a hard disk drive or SSD and you buy
你插入SATA总线。对的。然后，你会购买一个硬盘驱动器或固态硬盘，然后购买
this kind of hybrid device. And inside the device, you have the, you hide all the complexity. You
这种混合设备。在设备内部，你隐藏了所有的复杂性。
have a SSD, you have the hard disk drive and you have complex logic to deal and to use SSD,
你有一个固态硬盘，你还有硬盘驱动器，并且你有复杂的逻辑来处理和使用固态硬盘。
basically like a cache for the hard disk drives. Did I answer your question Gilbert?
基本上就像是硬盘驱动器的缓存。吉尔伯特，我回答了你的问题吗？
Okay. So yeah, it's complex, but it's hidden. The complexity is hidden. Okay. So announcements.
好的。是的，它很复杂，但是它是隐藏的。复杂性是隐藏的。好的。所以公告。
Homework 4 is due on Mondays. You're now, midterm to review. Now we have a time between 5 and 6,
作业4要在周一之前完成。现在是期中复习的时间。现在我们有一个在5点到6点之间的时间。
7 PM on Monday. Admitter 2 is Wednesday between 7 and 9 PM. And please read the updated proctoring
星期一晚上7点。Admitter 2是在星期三晚上7点到9点之间。请阅读更新后的监考说明。
guide. You can have an additional cheat sheet for this exam. Remember that this exam will cover
指南。你可以为这次考试准备一张额外的备忘单。记住这次考试将涵盖以下内容：
everything from the beginning of the semester, but we have more emphasize on the materials in the
本学期的所有内容，但我们更加强调教材中的内容。
first midterm. And the project is due next Friday. So next week it's a hard week,
第一次期中考试。而且项目下周五截止。所以下周会是一个忙碌的一周，
but it's again, after that, it will be easier.
但是再过一段时间，之后会变得更容易。
So now let's switch gears. Any question now about storage devices, what we learned over the last
那么现在让我们换个话题。关于存储设备的任何问题，我们在过去学到了什么？
and this lecture, hard disk drive and solid state drives?
这个讲座是关于硬盘驱动器和固态驱动器吗？
Okay. So right now, let's, we are going to switch the gears and we are going to talk about
好的。现在，让我们换个话题，我们要谈谈
performance and how to model performance. If you saw this kind of, even like device drivers are
性能和如何建模性能。如果你看到这种情况，甚至像设备驱动程序这样的东西也是如此。
pretty complex. You get a request, you enqueue the request because you may have multiple requests
非常复杂。你收到一个请求，你将请求加入队列，因为你可能有多个请求。
arriving at the same time, you serve the request. And by, from the point of view of the program who
同时到达时，您处理该请求。而且，从程序的角度来看，
made the request, it cares only about the end-to-end latency, but it's end-to-end latency
已经提出了请求，它只关心端到端的延迟，但它的端到端延迟是多少。
is divided or support is divided between multiple components. So we are going to learn a little bit
支持或分工被分配给多个组成部分。所以我们要学一点点。
about how to model those and let's try first to define what are the metrics we care about.
关于如何对这些进行建模，让我们首先尝试定义我们关心的指标是什么。
So the response time or latency is time to perform on operation is end-to-end time. And you have the
因此，响应时间或延迟是执行操作所需的时间，即端到端时间。而您有...
bandwidth or throughput is a rate to which you can perform operations, operation per second. And for
带宽或吞吐量是指您可以执行操作的速率，即每秒操作数。而对于其他内容，我会将其翻译成中文。
different devices, the operation can be different. Like for instance, it's a different metric here,
不同的设备，操作可能会有所不同。例如，这里使用的度量标准是不同的。
but all the metrics are over second, it's some quantity over second. Like files,
但是所有的指标都是以秒为单位的，它是一些每秒的数量。比如文件，
for files when you read and write is megabytes per second. For network is megabits per second.
对于文件的读写速度，以每秒兆字节（MB/s）为单位。对于网络速度，以每秒兆比特（Mbps）为单位。
When you say megabytes, it's power of two if you remember. Megabits for the network is power of 10.
当你说到兆字节时，如果你记得的话，它是以2的幂计算的。而网络中的兆比特是以10的幂计算的。
This is how you, for instance, one megabyte for files is 1024 kilobytes. One megabit
这是一个例子，例如，一个文件的一兆字节等于1024千字节。一个兆位
for network is 1000. Sorry, one megabit for network. What I'm saying? One megabyte for files,
网络速度是1000。抱歉，网络速度是一兆比特。我说的是什么？文件大小是一兆字节。
yeah, it's 1024 kilobytes I said correctly. One megabyte per second for network is 1000
是的，我说的没错，1024千字节。网络的速度是每秒1兆字节，相当于1000。
kilobytes per second. And then you have gigaflops operation per second, floating point operation
每秒千字节。然后你有每秒十亿次的浮点运算。
per second for automatic computation and things like that. Then you have a startup or overhead.
每秒自动计算和类似的事情。然后你有一个启动或开销。
It's a time to initiate an operation. This can be think about something like context switching.
现在是开始行动的时候了。这可以类比为上下文切换的概念。
And most of your operation are roughly linear in the number of bytes. So basically what happens
大部分操作都是按字节数大致线性增长的。所以基本上会发生什么呢？
in bytes. So basically, for instance, if you are going to,
以字节为单位。所以基本上，例如，如果你要...
the way you can model this operation, there is an overhead or a fixed cost to initiate the
你可以对这个操作进行建模的方式，存在一个开销或固定成本来启动。
operation. You pay on that operation no matter how much you transfer. And then it's a variable cost.
手续费。无论您转账金额多少，都需要支付手续费。之后，手续费是一个可变成本。
And the variable cost is n, how many bytes in this case you transfer over the bandwidth.
变量成本为n，那么在这种情况下，您通过带宽传输了多少字节？
So if you remember, we've seen this pretty much in the last lecture for hard disk drives. You
所以如果你还记得的话，我们在上一堂硬盘驱动器的课上已经看到过这个了。
remember you have the overhead, which was the seek time and rotation latency. No matter how much you
记住，你还有额外开销，包括寻道时间和旋转延迟。无论你有多少
read or write on a disk, you need to pay for that cost when you do that read and write.
读取或写入磁盘时，您需要支付相应的费用。
And then once you locate and you do the rest is sequential write, read and write,
然后一旦你找到并完成剩下的部分，就是顺序的写入、读取和写入。
then it's about how fast you are going to be able to read bits from the disk. And that is given by
那么这取决于你能够从磁盘中读取位的速度有多快。这由...给出。
how fast is the disk rotating and the rotation of the disk. And that is a variable part. You
磁盘的旋转速度有多快以及磁盘的旋转。而这是一个可变的部分。
read more, it's going to take more time. So this is a way to look at it again.
请再读一下，这会花费更多的时间。所以这是再次审视它的一种方式。
Basically, you have the user thread, which is going to initiate an input operation.
基本上，你有用户线程，它将启动一个输入操作。
Then you have a queue and you can have queue, this can be in controller or it can be in the
然后你有一个队列，你可以拥有队列，这可以在控制器中，也可以在...
operating system. It depends on the implementation, it depends on the device,
操作系统。这取决于具体的实现，取决于设备。
but there is a queue along the way where the requests are queued, if there are multiple
但是在这条路上有一个队列，请求会在队列中排队，如果有多个请求的话。
requests at the same time, then it's a controller and then it's finally the I/O device. So I/O
同时处理请求，首先是控制器，最后是输入/输出设备。所以I/O。
device service time. And this is how long I got the request, how long it takes to satisfy that
设备服务时间。这是我收到请求的时间，需要多长时间来满足请求。
request. So the metrics here are response times and throughput. Response time we saw in the previous
请求。这里的指标是响应时间和吞吐量。响应时间我们在之前看到了。
slide is S plus N over B. And what is the bandwidth? Now, the bandwidth is that one of
滑动是S加N除以B。那么带宽是什么？现在，带宽是其中之一。
the bandwidths we really care and it's from the user thread perspective, it is, we call the
我们真正关心的带宽是从用户线程的角度来看的，我们称之为
effective bandwidth. And the effective bandwidth is what we, when we are saying like, for instance,
有效带宽。而有效带宽是我们在说的时候，比如说，
if you remember, like how this drives, the throughput is very different when we are reading
如果你还记得，就像这样的驱动器，当我们在读取时，吞吐量是非常不同的。
randomly, random reads or sequential reads, right? It's very different if you remember.
随机读取或顺序读取，对吗？如果你还记得的话，这是非常不同的。
And that's effective bandwidth. So effective bandwidth for random reads is much lower than
这就是有效带宽。因此，随机读取的有效带宽要远低于
effective bandwidth for sequential reads. And the reason is, and effective bandwidth basically is,
顺序读取的有效带宽。原因是，有效带宽基本上是指，
it is how many bytes I'm sending, I read or operation I performed over how long it took me
我发送了多少字节，我读取或执行的操作花费了多长时间。
to read this and bytes, right? Or perform an operations. And the time it took to perform
阅读这个字节，对吗？或者执行一个操作。以及执行所需的时间。
this operation, you know, this latency, you know, from the previous slide, it says plus N over B.
这个操作，你知道的，这个延迟，你知道的，从前面的幻灯片上可以看到，它说的是加上 N 除以 B。
Or you can also, you know, a little bit of refactoring is B over one plus S B over N,
或者你也可以，你知道的，稍微重构一下，变成B除以（1加S）乘以B除以N。
right? So now you can see exactly, right? It's like, if you read only one byte, this is,
对吗？所以现在你能够清楚地看到了，对吗？就像，如果你只读取一个字节，这就是，
you know, the denominator will be dominated, this will be dominated by S by the overhead, right?
你知道，分母将会被主导，这将会被S通过开销主导，对吗？
And which is include controller time, queue delay, and things like that. And if you are going to have
并且其中包括控制器时间、队列延迟等等。如果你打算拥有的话
read a lot of bytes, this will be dominated by N. And actually the effective bandwidth
读取了大量的字节，这将由N主导。实际上，有效带宽是...
becomes similar with the bandwidth of the I/O device, like what in the case of a hard disk drive
变得与I/O设备的带宽相似，就像硬盘驱动器的情况一样。
with a bandwidth of sequential access. Any questions?
带有顺序访问的带宽。有什么问题吗？
Okay. So this is, we'll talk more about that plot you see on the right hand side.
好的。所以这个，我们将更多地谈论一下你在右侧看到的情节。
The only thing, and I'm going to repeat that a few times. The only thing to keep in mind is that
唯一需要记住的事情，我要重复几遍。唯一需要记住的事情是：
this is the kind of curve you are going to see. And this is on the X, Y axis, you have the
这是你将要看到的曲线类型。而在X、Y轴上，你有
utilization, right? How much utilization is about the load, which is offered to the device, the
利用率，对吗？关于负载的利用率是多少，即提供给设备的负载。
system over the capacity of the system, right? How much I can handle. And if you on X axis, you see
系统超出了系统的容量，对吗？我能处理多少？如果你在X轴上，你会看到什么？
the response, the Y axis, you see the response time. And this is how it looks like. Initially
响应，Y轴，你可以看到响应时间。这就是它的样子。最初的时候
it's going, you know, when the system is not very loaded, you have very little load,
还行，你知道的，当系统没有很大负荷时，你的负荷很小，
you get very good performance. The response time is very good, but you try to growth. And after
你的表现非常出色。响应时间非常好，但你可以尝试进一步提升。之后呢？
some point it's going to shut up. And if the load is equal to the capacity of the system, actually
有些时候它会停止工作。而且如果负载等于系统的容量，实际上
the response time can go to infinity, right? Can grow extremely fast, right? This is the same,
响应时间可以无限增长，对吗？可以增长得非常快，对吗？这是一样的。
like, remember, it's like highway. When the highway is free very late in the night or very
喜欢，记住，就像高速公路一样。当高速公路在深夜或清晨非常空旷时，
early in the morning, if you know, you'll go very fast, right? As a speed, like legal speed,
早上一大早，如果你知道的话，你会走得很快，对吗？就像速度快一样，合法的速度。
hopefully, right? And if, on the other hand, if you start like rush hour, right?
希望如此，对吗？而另一方面，如果你开始像交通高峰时间一样，对吗？
The delays can be shut up, right? And that's a big, obviously is a big problem. And then you
延误可以解决，对吗？显然这是一个大问题。然后你是指什么？
are stealing now is the capacity of the system, right? Because you've still added the capacity
现在偷窃的是系统的容量，对吗？因为你仍然增加了容量。
of the system because eventually all the cars still get home, right? So, none of them is
系统的好处是最终所有的车辆都能回家，对吗？所以，它们中没有一个是
stuck indefinitely. So, yes, let me give me one second. I think it's the sensor light.
卡住了，时间不确定。所以，是的，请给我一秒钟。我觉得是传感器灯。
Let me just start the light again.
让我重新打开灯。
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Sounds good. I need to move more.
听起来不错。我需要多动一些。
Contribute, so the factor to latency, you know, I can mention this kind of S,
贡献，所以延迟的因素，你知道，我可以提到这种S。
it's about hardware control, the IO service time, device service time, and so forth.
这是关于硬件控制、IO服务时间、设备服务时间等等的内容。
And, but the most interesting part, one of the most important things here is a queue, right?
而且，但最有趣的部分是，这里最重要的事情之一就是排队，对吧？
Because queue here, you have a lot of requests coming in, you queue them. So, you can spend a
因为在这里排队，你会有很多请求进来，你需要将它们排队。所以，你可以花费时间来处理它们。
lot of time in the queue. Actually, the reason response time shuts up is not because the device
在队列中花费了很多时间。实际上，响应时间变慢的原因并不是因为设备的问题。
the IO device time, service time, serving a request still takes the same amount of time.
IO设备的时间、服务时间以及处理请求所需的时间仍然是相同的。
Okay. So, this is very important to remember. The reasons is response time shuts up is because
好的。所以，这是非常重要的要记住。原因是响应时间变长。
a queue, because you have more and more requests as they have to wait for the previous request
一个队列，因为随着他们等待前一个请求，你会有越来越多的请求。
to be served. It's like you go into a grocery store. So, the time it takes a clerk
被服务。就像你进入一家杂货店一样。所以，一个店员花费的时间
to serve a customer doesn't depend on the queue size, right? It still takes the same time.
对于一个顾客的服务并不取决于队列的大小，对吗？它仍然需要相同的时间。
Maybe, you know, if the queue is long, maybe it's going even takes less because it's going to be
也许，你知道，如果队伍很长，也许时间会更短，因为它会变得更快。
hurry. But it's, you know, ideally it doesn't depend on the queue size. However, if there are
赶快。但是，你知道的，理想情况下它不取决于队列的大小。然而，如果有的话
many people in the store, you are going to wait more. Why? Because the queue is longer. Okay. So,
因为商店里有很多人，你需要等更久。为什么呢？因为排队的人更多。好的。那么，
one of the most interesting and relevant aspects is a queue, of a system is a queue. And this is
其中最有趣和相关的方面之一是队列，一个系统中的队列。这是一个非常重要的概念，它在许多领域都有应用。
what you are going to analyze a little bit. Okay. So, this is a way you typically present, you know,
你打算稍微分析一下。好的。所以，这是你通常展示的方式，你知道的。
you can model the system. You have arrivals and the arrival is a request which arrives,
你可以对系统进行建模。你有到达事件，到达事件是一个请求，它到达了。
like read request, write request, packets. These can be packets which arrive at the router and
喜欢阅读请求，写入请求，数据包。这些可以是到达路由器的数据包，也可以是从路由器发送出去的数据包。
things like that. And then you serve, you serve this request, like the server, right? You send
这样的事情。然后你提供服务，就像服务器一样，对吧？你发送
the data out, you serve the reads and writes and things like that. And then you have two times,
数据输出，你负责读取、写入等操作。然后你有两个时间，
DQ, which is a queuing time and TS is a serving time. And the response time is very, very,
DQ，是排队时间，TS是服务时间。而响应时间非常非常，
basically TQ plus TS, the queuing time plus the service time.
基本上，TQ加上TS，即排队时间加上服务时间。
And now you have another one, it's TA, which is, this is obviously you have here in this
现在你又有了另一个，它是TA，显然这是你在这里拥有的。
figure, it's on the x-axis, you have the time, and the TA is interarrival time. So basically
图中，x轴代表时间，而TA则表示到达时间间隔。所以基本上
the difference between two consecutive, between the arrival of two consecutive requests. Okay.
两个连续请求之间的差异，两个连续请求的到达之间的差异。好的。
And this is the arrival. And now on the y-axis, which is not shown, I should show here, if
这是到达地点。现在在y轴上，虽然没有显示，但我应该在这里显示，如果...
you go down, you move from down, is the time it takes, it's basically it's a response time.
你下去，你从下面移动，就是需要的时间，基本上就是响应时间。
Right. So what this shows here is that, sorry, it's yeah, what it shows here is basically
对的。所以这里显示的是，抱歉，是的，这里基本上显示的是
you have TQ is like, it's a time you spend in the queue. And then TS is a time you spend
你好，TQ代表的是排队时间，即你在队伍中等待的时间。而TS代表的是你花费的时间。
to service TS, to service that request. And after a while you have another request, which
为了服务TS，为了服务那个请求。过了一会儿，你又有了另一个请求，那个请求是什么？
is queue is very little. Here the queue is empty, but it's still probably a time because
队列很小。这里的队列是空的，但可能还需要一些时间，因为
you still need probably maybe to, even if it's one element in the queue, you need to
你可能仍然需要，即使只有一个元素在队列中，你也需要。
enqueue it and then get it out of the queue or just checking whether the queue is empty.
将其加入队列，然后将其从队列中取出，或者只是检查队列是否为空。
So there is still a little bit of time you are going to spend. Right. But here you are
所以你还要再花一点时间。对吧。但是你在这里。
dominated by the service time. Right. And you see, whenever you have a new request,
由服务时间主导。对的。你看，每当你有一个新的请求，
at least in this example, you are going to the queue is empty. Right. So every response
至少在这个例子中，你要去的队列是空的。对吧。所以每个回答都是
time, the response time on February request is going to take the same time. Okay. But
时间，2月份请求的响应时间将会保持不变。好的。但是
now let's do, okay. So let's introduce a few more metrics. So a few more metrics here are
现在让我们开始吧，好吗？那么让我们介绍几个更多的指标。这里有几个更多的指标：
basically the service rate. The service rate is basically is like how many operation you
基本上是服务速率。服务速率基本上就像是你能完成多少个操作。
can perform per second. Right. And basically this is one over TS. Right. It's like if,
每秒可以执行。对的。基本上这是1除以TS。对的。就好像，
for instance, if it takes me to serve a request, it takes 10 milliseconds to serve a request.
例如，如果我需要处理一个请求，那么处理一个请求需要10毫秒的时间。
How many I can do per second? One seconds over 10 milliseconds is 100. Then it's arrival
每秒钟我能做多少个？一秒钟超过10毫秒是100个。然后就到了。
rate. And this is one over TA. Right. This has a request per second. The request per
second is a measure of how many requests are made to a system or service in one second. It indicates the rate at which requests are being processed or handled. A higher request per second value generally means that the system is able to handle a larger volume of requests and is more efficient.
second it's the same. Right. It's like if I am getting every one request every 20 milliseconds,
第二个也是一样的。对的。就好像我每20毫秒收到一个请求。
then the Lambda, which is request per second, it's one over 20 milliseconds. One second
那么Lambda，也就是每秒请求数，就是每20毫秒一次。一秒钟。
over 20 milliseconds is 50. Right. And then it's utilization. Utilization is your arrival
超过20毫秒是50。对的。然后是利用率。利用率是你的到达。
rate over the service rate. Or if you plug in in this equation, the formula for the service
速率超过服务速率。或者如果你将其代入这个方程，就是服务的公式。
rate and the arrival rate, you are going to get the service time over the arrival time.
根据到达率和服务率，你将得到服务时间除以到达时间的结果。
Right. So basically what is this saying is that for instance, if you have the arrival
对的。所以基本上这句话的意思是，例如，如果你有到达的
time, it's 20 milliseconds and the service time is 10 milliseconds, then you are going
时间，它是20毫秒，服务时间是10毫秒，那么你就要去了。
to have 10 milliseconds over 20 milliseconds. It's 0.5. So utilization will be 50%, which
是指在20毫秒内有10毫秒的时间。这个比例是0.5。因此利用率将为50%。
kind of makes sense. Right. If I have one new request arriving every 20 milliseconds
有点说得通。对的。如果我每20毫秒收到一个新的请求
and one request, it takes me to process one request 10 milliseconds. This means that for
每个请求需要我处理10毫秒。这意味着对于每个请求，我需要花费10毫秒的时间。
each request, I'm going to spend 10 milliseconds and I'm going to wait another 10 milliseconds
每个请求，我将花费10毫秒的时间，然后再等待10毫秒。
to get the new request. And I'm going to be free half of my time. Right. Make sense? So
得到新的请求。我将有一半的时间是空闲的。对，合理吧？这样说清楚了吗？
what happens when Lambda is greater than the Mu and the arrival rate is greater than the
当Lambda大于Mu且到达率大于服务率时会发生什么？
service rate? What do you think it happens? It's a good question. If it's a for short
服务费率？你认为会发生什么？这是一个很好的问题。如果是短期的话，
interval of time, what is the burst? Then you are going to have the queue to absorb
时间间隔内，什么是突发？然后你将会有一个队列来吸收。
that burst. So the queue delay will going to increase. If it's long, it's for a long
那个突发事件会导致排队延迟增加。如果排队时间很长，那就要等很久了。
time, and it's just average arrival rate is greater than the average service rate, then
如果时间，且仅仅是平均到达率大于平均服务率，那么
the queue will grow indefinitely. The system is called to be in an unstable state. In general,
队列将无限增长。系统被称为处于不稳定状态。总的来说，
what we are going to analyze now in this lecture are systems which are stable. Means that the
我们现在要分析的是稳定的系统。这意味着系统的输出在一段时间内不会发生剧烈的变化。
arrival rate is not greater than the service rate. Okay. Good. So this is basically tells
到达率不大于服务率。好的。很好。所以基本上这就是在说明
you is about if TS over TA is small, then we are fine. And the queue time, the queuing
如果TS超过TA很小，那么我们就没问题。还有排队时间，排队。
delay is slow. But after some point, if you are going to get one, this is load, you see,
延迟很慢。但是在某个点之后，如果你要得到一个，这是负载，你知道的。
the load is for this plot from zero to one. This is TSA over TA, right? So before one
负载从零到一，这是TSA超过TA，对吗？所以在一之前。
is fine. It grows, but it grows a little bit. But if you are going to go over one, then
没问题。它在增长，但增长得很少。但如果你要超过一个，那么...
it's going to shut up, right? This is a queue delay. So it can be unbounded. So this is
它要关机了，对吧？这是一个队列延迟。所以它可能是无界的。所以这就是...
the answer to your question. Gilbert, if the arrival rate is greater than the service rate,
你的问题的答案是，Gilbert，如果到达率大于服务率，
then the queue will grow unbounded. So now let's see how the requests arrive in a burst
然后队列将无限增长。现在让我们看看请求是如何突然到达的。
and let's see what happens. And here on the vertical axis, I have queue depths. On the
咱们看看会发生什么。这里的纵轴表示队列深度。
horizontal axis is again the time. And here basically, I see here the queue depths. I'm
水平轴再次是时间。在这里，基本上我看到的是队列深度。我正在
going to have the first request in the queue. It's empty. It's going to be serviced immediately.
将在队列中有第一个请求。它是空的。将立即提供服务。
So this is where it's going to be the server. This is the server, the timeline for the server.
这就是服务器的位置。这是服务器，服务器的时间表。
So I get the request. I'm going to serve it here. But now I get the second request. So
所以我明白了你的请求。我会在这里为你提供服务。但是现在我收到了第二个请求。所以
if I'm getting the second request, I am going to have to queue it because the server is
如果我收到第二个请求，我将不得不将其排队，因为服务器正在忙碌。
satisfying the previous request. And now I get a new request. So new request again, I
满足之前的请求。现在我有一个新的请求。所以再次提出新的请求，我
need to queue it. Now I have two requests in the queue. Again, on the vertical axis
需要排队。现在我在队列中有两个请求。再次，在垂直轴上。
down, you have the size of the queue. So I have two in the queue right now. And now I
明白了，你想知道队列的大小。目前我有两个在队列中。现在我...
get another one. So it's again, the first request has unfinished being serviced. So
再拿一个。所以，又是这样，第一个请求还没有完成服务。所以
the queue is increasing by another one request. So I have three requests in the queue. Now
队列增加了另一个请求。所以我现在有三个请求在队列中。
I don't get anything more. So if I don't get anything more, I'm going to start serving,
我什么都不明白了。所以如果我什么都不明白了，我就要开始服务了。
say it's a five order. So I'm going to serve the first request in the queue, the wide request.
说它是第五个订单。所以我将会处理队列中的第一个请求，即广泛的请求。
Now while I serve the wide request, I still have two requests in the queue, the light
现在虽然我正在处理广泛的请求，但我还有两个请求在队列中，其中一个是轻松的。
blue one and the orange one. And then when I finish serving this request, I'm going to
蓝色的一个和橙色的一个。然后当我完成这个请求的时候，我要
serve the orange request and finally the light blue request. Okay. So this is what happens.
为橙色请求提供服务，最后是浅蓝色请求。好的。所以发生了什么事。
And now I have a new request and things like that. Any questions? So the point here is
现在我有一个新的请求之类的东西。有什么问题吗？所以这里的重点是什么？
that even the utilization is low, even if the average arrival rate is lower than the
即使利用率很低，即使平均到达率低于预期，
service rate, much lower even, you can still have occasional burst. So a lot of events
服务费率，甚至更低，你仍然可以偶尔有爆发。所以很多事件
or a lot of operation arrive at the same time. It's like rush hour, right? Over the entire
或者很多操作同时发生。就像高峰时间一样，对吗？在整个过程中
duration of a day, the arrival or the number of cars on the highway is significantly lower
一天的持续时间，高速公路上的到达或汽车数量显著较低。
than the capacity of the highway. But there are some bursts in rush hours, when the number
比高速公路的容量还要多。但在高峰时段会有一些突发情况，这时车辆数量超过了公路的承载能力。
of cars, it's almost at capacity and then you experience large events. So how do you
关于汽车，它几乎达到了容量上限，然后你会遇到大型活动。那么你如何处理呢？
model the burst arrival? Now there is a lot of mathematical models, but one of the most
常用的模型是泊松过程。泊松过程是一种随机过程，用于描述事件在时间上的随机到达。它假设事件之间的到达是独立且服从指数分布。泊松过程的数学模型可以用来模拟突发事件的到达情况。
elegant one is Poisson distribution or exponential distribution. Exponential distribution, and
优雅的一个是泊松分布或指数分布。指数分布，和
this is f of x is lambda, where lambda is the average arrival rate in this case, or
这里的f(x)是λ，其中λ是该情况下的平均到达率，或者
average mean for that distribution times e power minus Lx. And this is how it looks like,
该分布的平均值乘以e的负Lx次方。这就是它的样子。
this f of x. And this is a lambda, it's actually the mean arrival rate for this distribution,
这是f(x)。这个λ是指这个分布的平均到达率。
it's one over lambda. So actually lambda, I'm taking back, so lambda represent the interarrival
它是lambda的倒数。所以实际上，我撤回了lambda，lambda代表到达间隔。
time between the events, so mean arrival time is one over lambda. And the nice thing about
事件之间的时间间隔，所以平均到达时间是lambda的倒数。而且，关于这个的好处是
this exponential distribution is it is what is called memoryless. Memoryless means that
指数分布是一种被称为无记忆性的分布。无记忆性意味着
the future doesn't depend on the past, right? And it's counterintuitive because you are
未来不取决于过去，对吗？而且这是违反直觉的，因为你是...
not used to that. This will say, and maybe sometimes this happens, if you arrive at the
不习惯这样。这将会说，也许有时会发生这种情况，如果你到达的话。
station, right, Bath station, how long it takes for the next train to arrive doesn't
车站，对的，巴斯车站，下一班火车还要多久到达？
depend of when the previous train arrived, whether it arrived the last minute or whether
取决于前一班火车的到达时间，无论是在最后一分钟到达还是在其他时间到达。
it just leaves the station where it was 15 minutes ago. Okay. So this is what, but because
它刚刚离开了15分钟前的车站。好的。所以这是什么，但是因为
it's memoryless, it's much easier to model, right? It also says, if you look at this plot,
它是无记忆的，这样建模就容易得多，对吗？它还说，如果你看这个图，
that this means that the lot of events which are arriving in bursts, the interval between
这意味着到达的事件很多，而且是突发性的，它们之间的间隔时间
them is short, and there are some also very long intervals between events. So if you look
他们很短，而且事件之间也有一些非常长的间隔。所以如果你看
at the events on the timeline, there are bursts of events arriving together, so interarrival
在时间线上的事件中，有一连串的事件同时到达，因此可以称之为事件间隔。
between these events is small, and then you have long pauses, right? Long gaps. Any questions?
这些事件之间的间隔很短，然后你会有很长的停顿，对吗？很长的间隔。有任何问题吗？
You did learn exponential distribution, I hope in some of your math classes, right,
你在一些数学课上学过指数分布，对吗？
your statistics classes. Okay. And now with this distribution, what are the main metrics?
你的统计课。好的。现在有了这个分布，主要的指标是什么？
One of the most important metrics is the mean, obviously the mean of the distribution. And
其中一个最重要的指标是均值，显然是分布的均值。而且
you know how to compute the mean. It's like it's an integral or the sum, depending on
你知道如何计算均值。就像是一个积分或者求和，取决于
the discrete distribution of the P of t. So what is the probability that that event happens
t的离散分布的P。那么这个事件发生的概率是多少？
at time, you know, at t? What is the probability that you are going to have in this case, for
在某个时间，你知道，在t时刻？在这种情况下，你会有什么概率？
instance, an arrival after exactly t time units, and then you are going to multiply
例如，一个在确切的t时间单位后到达的实例，然后你将进行乘法运算。
with the t because the interarrival time, right? So, and this is the mean, right? If
是的，"t"代表到达时间间隔，对吗？那么，这是指平均值，对吗？如果是的话。
you have this variance of the square of the standard deviation, which is you multiply
你有标准差的平方的方差，即你将其乘以。
its sum of P of t multiplied by t square minus m square, and m is again the mean, and t is
它是P(t)乘以t的平方减去m的平方的和，其中m再次表示均值，而t是什么。
about, you know, how long, you know, the interarrival t, which happened is probability P of t. And
关于你说的，你知道，有多长时间，你知道，发生的间隔时间t的概率P。
then you square coefficient of variance, which is sigma square by the mean square. Okay.
然后你平方变异系数，即方差除以均值的平方。好的。
So I'm not going to derive this to you. I'm going to derive something more interesting
所以我不会给你推导这个。我会推导一些更有趣的东西。
to you. This you are supposed to know from some of your previous classes, you know, if
对你来说。这是你应该从之前的一些课程中知道的，你知道的，如果
not, this is just the formula you can write on your cheat sheet. But typically we are going
不，这只是你可以写在作弊纸上的公式。但通常我们会去做的是
to give you, if I am going to, we are going to ask you in a problem. But the most important
是的，如果我要给你，我们将要求你解决一个问题。但最重要的是
things here is to look at the value of C. The C captures the burstiness, it turns out.
这里要看的是C的价值。C捕捉到了突发性，结果表明。
So if C is zero, there is no variance. This also means the variance is zero square, square
所以如果C为零，就没有方差。这也意味着方差是零的平方，即零。
of standard deviation, which means that you have the interarrival between two events,
标准差是指两个事件之间的到达间隔，
between two requests is the same. Then if C is one, this means that you have exponential
在两个请求之间是相同的。那么如果C是一个，这意味着你有指数级的
distribution. It's a memoryless distribution, completely random, doesn't depend on the past.
分布。这是一个无记忆的分布，完全随机，不依赖于过去。
If C is 1.5, you have even a burstier distributions, the majority of C, say, for instance, or the
如果C是1.5，你会有更加爆炸性的分布，大部分的C，比如说，例如，或者
majority of the interarrival times are much smaller than the average. So the more C increases,
大多数的到达间隔时间远小于平均值。所以C越大，
the more bursty you have the distribution, meaning a lot of events coming, a lot of requests
你的分布越爆发，意味着有很多事件发生，有很多请求。
coming together and then long gaps. And obviously the more burstiness you have, the larger the
间隔越长。显然，爆发性越大，间隔越长。
queue will be, at least during these events. If there is no variance and if your furlough
排队将会至少在这些事件期间存在。如果没有变化，如果你的停职期间
is lower than the service capacity, then you have no queues.
如果需求量低于服务能力，那么就不会有排队。
So let's talk more about queuing theory. And the queuing theory is very simple. You have
所以让我们更多地谈谈排队理论。排队理论非常简单。你有
to make some assumption about the distributions. You have to make some assumptions about how
对于分布进行一些假设。你必须对如何进行假设做出一些假设。
long it takes to serve the request. What is the distribution to serve a request? What
是什么分布来服务请求？需要多长时间来处理请求？
is the distribution of arrivals? And based on this, then you are going to get some formula
这是到达的分布吗？根据这个，你将得到一些公式。
which will give you the service response time and the queuing delay. That's what it is.
这将为您提供服务响应时间和排队延迟。就是这样。
So before talking more about this queuing and giving you those formulas about response
所以在更多地讨论排队问题之前，给你提供一些关于响应的公式。
time and everything, let's go through this little law. And it's a very powerful law.
时间和一切，让我们来仔细研究这个小法则。这是一个非常强大的法则。
It's very simple, deceptive simple and very general. And this is what it says. It says
这非常简单，简单得令人误解，而且非常普遍。它的意思是这样的。它说
you have a bunch of arrivals and which are served by a system, a bunch of requests coming
您有一批到达的人员，这些人员由一个系统提供服务，还有一批请求正在到来。
to a system, they are serving the system. And you know what is the average mean of,
对于一个系统来说，他们是为系统服务的。而你知道平均数的意思是什么吗？
what is the average arrivals for the request and what is the average service for the request.
请求的平均到达量是多少，请求的平均服务量是多少。
And what little law is giving you is how many on the average, how many requests are waiting
而你所提供的少量法律是平均有多少个请求在等待。
in the queue to be served. That's all. And the formula is a number of requests. Here
在队列中等待服务。就这些。而公式是请求的数量。
I pick jobs. It's equal to the mean arrival time, lambdas, time, the response time, mean
我选择工作。这等于平均到达时间，λ，时间，响应时间，平均值。
response time. Okay. So this is what it is. That's it. And the beauty of it is that this
响应时间。好的。所以这就是它的情况。就是这样。而且它的美妙之处在于这一点。
is true regardless of the structure of the arrivals. How what is a burst doesn't depend
是真实的，不论到达的结构如何。什么是突发并不取决于它的结构。
on the distribution. Doesn't depend on the distribution of the arrival, doesn't depend
在分布上。不依赖于到达的分布，不依赖于
on the distribution of the service time because the results holds for the means. Right. It
关于服务时间的分布，因为结果适用于均值。对的。
does assume though that the arrivals are not larger. The arrival rate is not larger than
假设到达量不会更大。到达率不会超过
mean arrival rate is not larger than the mean service rate. And here is an example just
平均到达率不得大于平均服务率。这里有一个例子。
to give you the, to capture that intuition. On X you have times, and let's say you have
为了给你提供，捕捉那种直觉。在X上你有一些时间，假设你有...
a new job or request for some reason here, you know, I put jobs coming to the system
有一个新的工作或请求出现在这里，你知道，我把工作放到系统里。
and being serviced. And you have one job every second. So this is deterministic arrival.
并且正在接受服务。你每秒钟只有一个工作。所以这是确定性到达。
Every second you have a new job, exactly every second. Any job takes to serve five seconds.
每秒钟你都有一份新工作，确切地说是每秒钟。任何工作都需要花费五秒钟的时间来完成。
Right. This is what you have, right? You have the first job starts here, you serve five
是的。这是你所拥有的，对吗？你有第一份工作从这里开始，你服务五个人。
seconds. The second job starts, serve five seconds and so forth. So now how many of the
秒。第二个工作开始，持续五秒，以此类推。那么现在有多少个？
jobs you have in the system? At any given time, you can draw a line and the number of
你在系统中有哪些工作？在任何给定的时间，你可以画一条线，然后写下数量。
jobs you have in the system, it's the number of jobs this line is going to intersect. And
你在系统中的工作是指这条线将要相交的工作数量。而且
how many have? Five. Right. And what is the formula saying? Number of jobs, average number
有多少个？五个。对的。那么公式是说什么？工作数量，平均数量。
of jobs in the system is equal with average or the mean arrival rate, which was one times
系统中的作业数量等于平均到达率或平均到达速率，即一次。
the mean service response time, which is five. So it's five. Okay. So let's, let me try to
将这句话翻译成英文：the mean service response time, which is five. So it's five. Okay. So let's, let me try to
The mean service response time is five. So it is five. Okay. So let's, let me try to.
derive this formula for you. Okay. So let's talk, let's say now we are going to be general,
推导这个公式给你。好的。那么让我们来讨论，假设现在我们要进行一般化的讨论，
right? The jobs can arrive at any time. They can take any amount of time to be, to be,
对吗？工作可以随时到来。它们可能需要不同的时间来完成。
they are going to be in the system and yeah. So let's talk L of I is the response time
他们将会进入系统，是的。所以让我们来谈谈I的响应时间。
of job I and N of T is a number of jobs in the system at time T. Right? So this is N
工作I和N的T是系统中在时间T的作业数量。对吗？所以这就是N。
of T at this particular time. So you want to see what is the system occupancy? How many
在这个特定的时间，你想知道系统的占用情况是多少？有多少人在使用系统？
on the average? What is the number of jobs in the system? This N, the average of N of
平均来说？系统中的工作数量是多少？这个N，是N的平均值。
This is what you want to compute. The average of N of T. OK.
这是你想要计算的内容。N个T的平均值。好的。
So before, so this is the remember is what I want to get.
所以之前，这是我想要得到的记忆。
Now, let's do some a little bit of math. Let's assume for simplicity that the height
现在，让我们做一些简单的数学题。为了简单起见，假设高度为
of one of these things, jobs, which I represent here, it's one.
这些事物之一，工作，我在这里代表的就是其中之一。
OK, so really the N of T represents the height of this shape, right, the blue shape.
好的，所以实际上T的N代表的是这个形状的高度，对吗，蓝色的形状。
So in this case, the height is four, so you have four jobs in the system. Right.
所以在这种情况下，高度是四，所以你在系统中有四个工作。对的。
Now, the area of each of these boxes is what? It's I of I, it's I of I, the length,
现在，这些盒子的面积是多少？它是I的I，它是I的I，长度，
it's how long it takes the job response time for that particular job I times one,
这是特定工作的响应时间，我乘以1，需要多长时间。
because we said that by convention, we say that the height is one. So the area S is S1,
因为我们约定俗成地说，高度为1。所以面积S就是S1。
the total area here for this all the jobs within the time capital T is S1 plus S2 plus say SK.
这里所有工作在时间T内的总面积是S1加上S2再加上SK。
It's and it's equal to is L1 plus L2 plus LK because SI is equal to is LI times one,
这是一个等式，它等于L1加L2加LK，因为SI等于LI乘以1。
which is equal to is LI. And why do I do this? Right. Now, what I want to compute is to remember
等于的是LI。为什么我要这样做呢？对了。现在，我想要计算的是记住。
that average fuel occupancy is what it is. It's this area over T. Right. This is what I'm doing.
平均燃料占用率就是它所表示的。它是T上的这个区域。对的，这就是我正在做的事情。
I have this shape, which I have this area, and I need to divide on the length of the area,
我有一个形状，它有一个面积，我需要根据面积的长度进行划分。
which is T in this case, to get to the average height of the area. Right. The N average,
在这种情况下，T代表的是达到该地区平均身高所需的时间。对的。N代表平均值。
the average number of jobs in the system is the average height of the shape, which is S over T.
系统中的平均作业数量是形状的平均高度，即S除以T。
Right. But now we know that S is L of one plus L of two plus L of K over D now. And now the
正确。但现在我们知道S是L的一加上L的二加上L的K除以D。而现在
beauty of it, I need to do only the one thing. I need to divide by N total and multiply with N
美妙之处在于，我只需要做一件事。我需要将总数除以N，然后乘以N。
total. Right. And N total is a total number of jobs which arrived during this time T
总数。对的。而N总是在这段时间T内到达的工作总数。
and are serviced during this time T. Right. So it's the same equation, the equation from the
并且在这段时间T内进行维护。对的。所以这是同一个方程，来自于...
previous one, but I'm going to divide by N total and I'm now going to multiply by N total. N total
之前的一个，但我现在要除以总数N，然后再乘以总数N。总数N
in this example, it will be K. Right. Because it's what I showed here, like K. Right. But now
在这个例子中，它将是K。对的。因为这是我在这里展示的，就像K。对的。但现在
I just reverted one, but it's the same thing. It's N total over T plus L1 plus LK over N total.
我刚刚还原了一个，但是它是一样的。它是N总数除以T加L1加LK除以N总数。
But here is a thing right now. What is N total over T?
但是现在有一个问题。N总数除以T是什么？
So I have N total jobs arriving during time T. So N total over T, it's an average,
所以在时间T内，我总共有N个工作到达。所以N除以T，得到的是一个平均值。
it's how many, it's N total over T, it's arrival rate.
这是多少，是N总数除以T，是到达率。
I mean arrival rate. If I tell you, I have 100 jobs and they arrived in 10 seconds. Right. And
我是指到达速率。如果我告诉你，我有100个任务，它们在10秒内到达。对的。而且
I ask you, what is the arrival rate? What do you do? You say 100 over 10 seconds. Oh, it's 10 jobs
我问你，到达率是多少？你做什么？你说每10秒100个。哦，那就是10个任务。
per second. This is Lambda. And what is L1 plus LK over N total?
每秒。这是Lambda。那么L1加LK除以N总是多少？
L1 is the average response time for first job.
L1是第一份工作的平均响应时间。
L2 is the average response time of the second job. If I add all these jobs up, the response
L2是第二个任务的平均响应时间。如果我将所有这些任务加起来，响应时间的总和是多少？
time of all the jobs, if I sum up the average response time of all jobs and I divide by the
所有工作的时间，如果我将所有工作的平均响应时间相加，然后除以
number of jobs, what do I get? The average response time. So here you are. The average
工作数量，我会得到什么？平均响应时间。所以这里是。平均的。
occupancy or the average number of jobs in the system is equal with the average arrival rate
占用率或系统中的平均作业数等于平均到达率。
of these jobs plus times, sorry, the average response time of a job. Make sense? Any questions?
这些工作的总和再加上时间，抱歉，是工作的平均响应时间。有意义吗？有任何问题吗？
Okay. So again, I want to emphasize like this is a great,
好的。所以再次强调，我想说这是一个很棒的，
very elegant law and because it's so simple and yet is so general. It doesn't make any
非常优雅的法律，因为它如此简单却又如此普遍。它不会造成任何
assumption of distributions. You need only to know the average arrival rate and average response time.
分布的假设。您只需要知道平均到达率和平均响应时间。
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay. So now let's do a little bit of queuing theory and unfortunately, and I apologize here,
好的。现在让我们来谈一下排队理论，不过很遗憾，我在这里要道歉，
I am going to give you some results. I'm not going to derive anymore. So hopefully you enjoyed
我将给你一些结果。我不再推导了。希望你喜欢。
the previous derivation. But let's talk a little bit about that, about this to give you some,
之前的推导。但是让我们稍微谈一下这个，关于这个来给你一些，
you know, queuing results, queuing theory results. First of all, like I mentioned,
你知道，排队结果，排队理论结果。首先，就像我之前提到的，
here we only assume that the system is what you call in a queue level, which is
在这里
basically the number, the arrival rate is not larger, is no larger than the service side.
基本上，数量的到达速率不会超过服务端。
We also assume that the queue has no limits. So therefore we don't drop requests.
我们还假设队列没有限制。因此，我们不会丢弃请求。
Okay. Let's assume that the time between two arrivals is random and is memoryless,
好的。让我们假设两次到达之间的时间是随机的，并且没有记忆效应。
it's exponentially distributed. When the time, inter-arrival time between
它是指数分布的。当时间，到达时间间隔之间的时间
successive requests, it's exponentially distributed. We are saying that that arrival
连续的请求，它们是指数分布的。我们说的是到达的请求数量。
is for us all, by the way, if you hear that. So arrival rate, Lambda, service rate is Mu,
是为我们所有人准备的，顺便说一下，如果你听到了。所以到达率是Lambda，服务率是Mu，
one over the T service. This is a TS. Previously, it was denoted by TS, it's a time to serve
一次T服务。这是一个TS。以前，它被表示为TS，它是一个服务时间。
the request. Okay. So you have Lambda, mean number of arriving, request, customer, jobs per second,
这个请求。好的。所以你有Lambda，表示每秒到达的请求、顾客、任务的平均数量。
mean time to serve the customer, it's say M, square coefficient of variance, this is one,
平均服务时间，即M，方差系数，为1。
in the case, remember, in the case of exponential distribution, Mu is a service rate, you know that,
在这种情况下，请记住，在指数分布的情况下，Mu是一个服务速率，你知道的。
one of the TS, time to service that request. Utilization, again, you know that,
其中一个TS，是时候处理那个请求了。利用率，再次提醒你，你知道的。
your SOSA formula is a number, is arrival rate over the mean arrival rate over mean service rate.
你的SOSA公式是一个数字，表示到达率除以平均到达率与平均服务率的比值。
Which is Lambda over Mu or Lambda time deserve, right? Here, I just
想确认一下，是Lambda除以Mu还是Lambda乘以Deserve，对吗？在这里，我只需要确认一下。
replace the Mu definition, which is one of the service time. Now, and if you do that,
替换掉Mu的定义，它是服务时间的一种。现在，如果你这样做的话，
you get the utilization, it's arrival rate times the service time, I mean service time.
你理解了，利用率是到达率乘以服务时间，我是说服务时间。
What do you want to compute? Time spent in the queue, that's what I want to compute.
你想要计算什么？我想要计算在队列中花费的时间。
We also want to compute the length of the queue, which is, what is the length of the queue?
我们还想计算队列的长度，也就是说，队列的长度是多少？
The length of the queue is Lambda of TQ, right? Because the system here is a queue,
队列的长度是TQ的Lambda，对吗？因为这里的系统是一个队列。
this is what I'm saying, the system here is a queue, right? So you can apply little,
这就是我说的，这里的系统是一个队列，对吧？所以你可以逐步申请。
low to the queue itself, or you can apply to the entire system. Here is for the queue itself.
您可以将其应用于队列本身，或者您可以将其应用于整个系统。这里是针对队列本身的设置。
Okay, so let's see. Like I said, when you have exponential distribution for the arrival rate,
好的，让我们来看看。就像我说的，当到达率服从指数分布时，
inter-arrival rates for the requests, this is also called Poisson arrival process.
请求的到达间隔率，也被称为泊松到达过程。
We assume here that we have one server, right? We can have a, there are scenarios in which you have
我们在这里假设我们只有一个服务器，对吗？我们可以有一个，在某些情况下你可能会有多个。
multiple servers and you send the request to, if one server accepts a request, you can send
多个服务器，你发送请求到其中一个服务器，如果一个服务器接受了请求，你可以发送
the request to another server. And it's memoryless service, so again, let's assume that the service
向另一个服务器发送请求。而且它是无记忆的服务，所以再次假设该服务
distribution is also exponential, so it's memoryless.
分布也是指数分布，因此它是无记忆的。
So this system, which Poisson arrival process, memoryless service time,
这个系统具有泊松到达过程和无记忆服务时间。
and one server is called MM1Q.
而其中一个服务器被称为MM1Q。
It's again, one server, inter-arrival times are exponentially distributed, service time
再次是一个服务器，到达时间间隔服从指数分布，服务时间
are exponentially distributed. And in this case, the queuing time, it's equal with the service time
服从指数分布。在这种情况下，排队时间等于服务时间。
times U over one minus U, where U is the utilization.
时间U除以1减U，其中U是利用率。
Now for general distribution, if you have the service distribution, so if the service time is
现在进行一般分发，如果您有服务分发，那么如果服务时间是多少。
a general distribution and you know for that one only the variance, the square root of variance,
一个普通的分布，你只知道它的方差，方差的平方根。
the C, then this is a formula. It's very similar formula. It's
C，然后这是一个公式。这是非常相似的公式。
one over, let me just move the, it's service time times one over two plus one plus C,
一分之一，让我把它移动一下，这是服务时间乘以一分之二再加一再加C。
this is again square root of, square of variance, times one over one minus U.
这是方差的平方根再乘以一除以一减去U。
Okay, so the important takeaway from this equation, it's a very important aspect here,
好的，所以这个方程的重要要点是，这是一个非常重要的方面。
is this fact, this is one over one minus U. Why is this important? Because this tells you
这是事实，这是1除以1减去U。为什么这很重要？因为这告诉你
when the utilization is small, this factor is small, right? It's
当利用率很低时，这个因素也很小，对吗？
basically U over one if U is very small. But what happens when the utilization approaches one,
基本上，当利用率非常小的时候，U超过1。但是当利用率接近1时会发生什么呢？
which is equivalent with a service rate, arrival rate approaching the service rate, what happens?
当服务速率和到达速率接近时，会发生什么情况？
It gets very large, the Q becomes very large. So another important aspect here is,
它变得非常大，Q值变得非常大。因此，这里还有另一个重要的方面，
and this is food for thought, is something which is not intuitive either.
这是一个值得思考的问题，也不是一件直观的事情。
If U goes close to one, although it's not yet one, the queuing time grows to infinity.
如果U接近于1，尽管还不等于1，排队时间会无限增长。
And then we ask, well, but hey, wait a minute. If U is one, we should be fine,
然后我们问道，嗯，等一下。如果U是一个，那我们应该没问题了，
because the arrival rate is not greater than the service rate. But if U is one,
因为到达率不大于服务率。但是如果U等于1，
the queuing is infinity. Why is that?
排队是无限的。为什么会这样？
We'll talk more next lecture and you are not going to be asked this during the exam.
我们下一堂课会再详细讨论，而且考试时不会问到这个问题。
But if the system is very bursty, there can be gaps.
但是如果系统非常突发，可能会出现间断。
And during these gaps, there is nothing in system.
在这些间隙期间，系统中没有任何东西。
And you lose that time, you lost, you never comes back. Because the bursts you are going to get in
而你失去了那段时间，你输了，它永远不会回来。因为你即将获得的机会会消失。
the future are going to, then if you eliminate that gap, the number of arrival you are going
未来将会发生变化，如果你消除这个差距，你所到达的数量将会增加。
to get in the future is going to be greater than the server capacity. Right?
未来的需求量将会超过服务器的容量。对吗？
So because this kind of this gaps where the system doesn't get,
所以因为这种系统无法理解的间隙，
doesn't do anything, when you have a very bursty arrival,
当你有一个非常突发的到达时，它什么都不做。
this is a wasted time, it's a wasted capacity. So that capacity you cannot get back.
这是浪费的时间，是浪费的能力。所以那个能力你无法重新获得。
So that's why you can... you fall behind in terms of capacity and you remain always behind.
所以这就是为什么你能够...你在容量方面落后，并且始终落后的原因。
Okay, so it's... I'm trying to give you an intuition, so it's like...
好的，所以是这样的...我试图给你一个直观的理解，所以就像是...
it's not easy to get the intuition and... but this is good.
这并不容易理解和掌握，但这是好的。
Okay. What else I wanted to say here? Oh, by the way, you notice that for the general service time
好的。我还想在这里说什么呢？哦，顺便说一下，你注意到一般的服务时间是多久了吗？
distribution, the formula for the queuing delay, if exponential... you remember for exponential
分布，排队延迟的公式，如果是指数分布...你记得指数分布的公式吗？
distribution, what was C? One. So if C is one, the equation, the queuing time for the general service
分布，C是什么？是一。所以如果C是一，那么方程中的排队时间是一般服务的。
distribution is going to reduce to the formula which you should expect for the exponential
分布将会减少到指数函数的公式，这是你应该期望的。
distribution. Let's take now simple examples and then we are going to conclude the lectures.
分发。现在让我们举一些简单的例子，然后我们将总结讲座。
Let's say the user request, you have 10 requests of... you want 8 kilobytes disk,
让我们假设用户请求，您有10个请求...您想要8千字节的磁盘。
write 10 requests of each for 8 kilobytes data, and the request and the service are exponentially
写下每个8千字节数据的10个请求，请求和服务都是指数增长的。
distributed. Average service is 20 milliseconds and this is controller six times, rotation, latency,
分布式。平均服务时间为20毫秒，这是控制器旋转六次的延迟。
and transfer time. And how you utilize this is a disk, right? So utilization, this is a formula,
和传输时间。你是如何利用这个的，是一个磁盘对吧？所以利用率，这是一个公式，
remember, it's lambda times the service time, these are the formula. Average time to spend in
记住，这是λ乘以服务时间，这是公式。平均花费时间为
the queue to queue, average number of requests in the queue. Now this is LQ denoted here. What is
队列的队列，队列中的平均请求数量。这里用LQ表示。请问是什么意思？
the average response time for disk request? So this is the average response time. It's very simple
磁盘请求的平均响应时间是多少？所以这就是平均响应时间。非常简单。
that the sum between the time you spend in the queue and time to serve is a request.
排队等候时间和服务时间之和是一个请求。
Okay, so let's do the computation. Lambda, you have 10 requests of 8 kilobytes disk per second.
好的，那我们来进行计算。Lambda，你每秒有10个8千字节的磁盘请求。
So lambda, you have average arriving number of customers or request is 10 per second. Average
So lambda, 您每秒平均到达的顾客或请求数量是10个。Average
time to service a customer or request 10 milliseconds. It was given here, if you remember,
每个客户或请求的服务时间为10毫秒。如果你还记得的话，这是给出的时间。
this is one average service time. Server utilization is lambda times the service time
这是一个平均服务时间。服务器利用率是λ倍的服务时间。
is 0.2. Queuing time, now you are going to apply because everything gets exponentially distributed.
是的，0.2是排队时间，现在你要申请，因为所有事情都是指数分布的。
Then you use a formula, which is a TS, service time times utilization over one minus utilization,
然后你使用一个公式，即TS，服务时间乘以利用率除以一减去利用率，
and you get five milliseconds. Average length of the queue is lambda times TQ is 0.05.
并且你得到了五毫秒。队列的平均长度是λ乘以TQ的0.05。
And average time the customer spend in the system is a queuing time plus the service time
顾客在系统中平均花费的时间是排队时间加上服务时间。
service to 20 milliseconds plus 5 milliseconds. Here is 25 milliseconds.
服务需要20毫秒加上5毫秒。这里总共是25毫秒。
There are a lot of materials here. You have some pointers if you are interested more in the
这里有很多材料。如果你对这方面更感兴趣，我可以给你一些建议。
queuing theory. It's great. This is a fair game. This is a mistake. You are going to get this in
排队理论。很棒。这是一个公平的游戏。这是一个错误。你将会得到这个。
midterm 2, not 3. Sorry for the typo. So this lecture is included for midterm 2. And with that,
期中考试2，不是3。对于打字错误我很抱歉。所以这个讲座包括在期中考试2中。除此之外，
I am done. So in summary, and remember about, we look at this, how we are going to model the
我已经完成了。所以总结一下，并记住，我们要考虑的是，我们将如何对其进行建模。
systems. And these systems are modeled, they have a queue. And you spend some time in the queue,
系统。而这些系统是建模的，它们有一个队列。而你在队列中花费一些时间，
plus have a fixed overhead, like rotation latency and so forth, and you have a transfer.
此外，还有一些固定的开销，比如旋转延迟等等，再加上数据传输。
Then this will impact the effective bandwidth. Effective bandwidth is not like the device
那么这将影响有效带宽。有效带宽不同于设备。
bandwidth because of this fixed overhead. Then we learn a little bit about this queuing theory.
由于这个固定的开销，带宽受限。然后我们稍微了解一下排队论。
And in particular, I gave you the formulas for the queuing delay for MM1 queues, everything is
而且特别地，我给你了MM1队列的排队延迟公式，一切都是正确的。
exponentially distributed, interarrival time and the service time. And MG1 queue arrival times are
指数分布、到达间隔时间和服务时间。而MG1队列的到达时间是什么。
still interarrival time, are still exponentially distributed, but the service time has a general
仍然是到达间隔时间，仍然服从指数分布，但服务时间具有一般分布。
distribution. And remember, this is a formula for the queuing time for the general distribution of
分布。记住，这是一个适用于一般分布的排队时间公式。
the service time. And remember that in both cases, both MM1 and MG1 queues, when the utilization
服务时间。请记住，在两种情况下，无论是MM1队列还是MG1队列，当利用率
approaches one, then the latency goes to infinity, the queuing delay and therefore the response time
当一个请求接近时，延迟会变得无限大，排队延迟和因此响应时间也会增加。
goes to infinity. So I'm stopping here. Good luck to at the midterm and really good luck for the
期中考试。祝你好运，也祝你在期中考试中好运！
next week. If you have any questions, please don't hesitate to ask on Piazza. And yeah, I'll see you
下周。如果你有任何问题，请毫不犹豫地在Piazza上提问。嗯，我会见到你的。
next week.
下周。